Junya Wang

I am a full-stack product designer with a decade of experience crafting digital solutions by driving every step of the design process from leading stakeholder workshop, user research, user experience/interface design, to prototype, usability testing and iteration. I also advocated, established and evolved design systems for large-scale teams.

My clients include: 3M, New York University, PwC, Barnes and Noble, Tempur-Pedic, ReadyRefresh, lululemon athletica, Vancity, etc.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Design Lead, Cognizant

Apr 2023 - Present · Remote

- Solved complex UX challenges for an enterprise-focused project management system
- Led the revamp to version 2.0, integrating a fresh aesthetic and aligning with both a novel design system and emerging technologies
- Pioneered, established and evolving a product-tailored design system, bridging the disparity between the overarching organizational design framework and the intricate needs of individual teams

Senior Product Designer, Softvision

Apr 2019 - Mar 2023 · Remote

- Led discovery workshops to align client objectives with optimal product strategy
- Directed design team, setting achievable scope, providing accurate estimates, and ensuring timely, high-quality deliverables
- Drove end-to-end design processes, encompassing product strategy, user research, interface design, prototyping, and usability testing
- Conducted in-depth user research and usability testing, refining product strategy and user experience iteratively
- Provided mentorship to fellow designers, offering tailored guidance to nurture their career development

Product Designer, Momentus

Jul 2014 - Mar 2019 · Vancouver, Canada

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design digital experiences spanning mobile applications, web apps, and innovative platforms like smart tables/mirrors
- Pioneered AR/VR design and independently developed an Android VR app, catalyzing the company's entry into the AR/VR industry

EDUCATION

Simon Fraser University, BSc. Interactive Arts and Technology

2009 - 2014 · Vancouver, Canada

ayajunya.com

ayajunya@gmail.com +1 778 859 9861

COMPETENCIES

Product Design & Strategy
Design System
Service Design
User Research
Usability Testing
AR/VR Design
Inclusive Design
Front-end Development

TOOLS

Figma, Stark, Sketch, Adobe CC, InVision, Zeplin, Miro, Mural, Lookback, Sublime

CERTIFICATES

Scrum.org

Professional Scrum Master I Professional Scrum Product Owner I

Google

Google Analytics for Beginner

AlterSpark

Emotional Design Psychology Psychology for Digital Behavior Change

IDEO

Human-Centered Service Design

Nielson Norman Group

Becoming a UX Strategist